<?xml version="1.0"?>

<tolerances>

 <tolerance name="standard_plate_thickness" value = ".01" units = "mm">
  The thickness for a given family/part_num/material is specified in the 
  pdm database.  However, the system does allow several ways to alter the
  plate thickness especially when using plate macros.  This tolerance is used to
  determine when then thickness of a plate differs from the standard value.
</tolerance>

 <tolerance name="min_area_outer_contour" value = "100" units = "mm2">
  This is basically the minimum surface area of a plate.  The main purpose is
  to detect invalid plate geometry which often results in little pieces of a 
  plate hanging off in space.  The plate seems to look fine but the little piece
  is often treated by the system as being the main plate.
  17 June 2003 - This tolerance is used when sending plates to spades.
  It is tighter than the one that the hull section uses.
</tolerance>

 <tolerance name="min_plate_area" value = "500" units = "mm2">
  This is used during snapshot to check for small plates.
  It used to have a hardcoded value of 1000.
  It really should be the same as min_area_outer_contour but thats
  up to the customer to decide.
</tolerance>

 <tolerance name="min_web_area" value = "500" units = "mm2">
  This is used during snapshot to check for small beams.
</tolerance>
 
 <tolerance name="min_cut_length" value = "10" units = "mm">
  This is used during snapshot to check for small beams.
</tolerance>
  
 <tolerance name="min_area_hole" value = "20" units = "mm">
  The smallest hole that can be cut into a plate
</tolerance>

 <tolerance name="contour_gap" value = ".01" units = "mm">
  The system sometimes leaves tiny gaps between what should be continous
  curves.
</tolerance>

 <tolerance name="edge_not_closed" value = "1.0" units = "mm">
  When a plate has two or more production edges then individual edges should not be closed.
  A closed edge usually means invalid geometry in the original plate.
  The value is pretty high since each edge should also have some real length.
</tolerance>

 <tolerance name="min_dis_hole_contour" value = "25.6" units = "mm">
  Minimum distance between a hole (i.e. inner coutout) and the outer contour
  of a plate.
</tolerance>

 <tolerance name="min_dis_hole_centers" value = "5.0" units = "mm">
  Used to detect duplicate holes by comparing their centers.
</tolerance>

 <tolerance name="min_dis_hole_hole" value = "5.0" units = "mm">
  Used to detect when holes are too close together.
</tolerance>

 <tolerance name="plate_hole_area_factor" value = "1.1">
  The area of a given hole multiplied by this factor should be less that the
  total area of the plate.  Trying to flag big holes especially when invalid
  geometry makes it appear that a hole is bigger than the plate.
</tolerance>

 <tolerance name="min_hole_dimension" value = "19.0" units = "mm">
  Smallest possible half width, halg height or radius
  .75 inches rounded down slightly since some ellipses are just under
</tolerance>

 <tolerance name="min_line_arc_seg_len" value = "0.1" units = "mm">
  The process of converting a bspline curve to line-arcs needs to ensure that
  the curve is not broken down into too small of chunks or else it can't be cut.
  The value is the shortest any particular segment can be. It really should be
  bigger than what it is but get too many hits for bigger values.  Use it to
  improve the line-arc process.
</tolerance>

 <tolerance name="ellipse_is_circle" value = "1.0" units = "mm">
  Sometime the bspmath routines have trouble makine ellipses that are almost
  circular.  This value says to treat any ellipse whose width and depth are
  within this tolerance as a circle. 
</tolerance>

 <tolerance name="min_cog_changed" value = "10.0" units = "mm">
  Used to flag when the cog of a piece or stage has changed.
</tolerance>

 <tolerance name="min_ref_changed" value = "10.0" units = "mm">
  Used to flag when the ref point of a piece or stage has changed.
</tolerance>

 <tolerance name="min_len_changed" value = "1.0" units = "mm">
  Used to flag when the cut length of a beam has changed.
</tolerance>

 <tolerance name="min_area_changed" value = "1.0" units = "mm2">
  Used to flag when the area of a piece has changed.
</tolerance>

 <tolerance name="min_mass_changed" value = "10.0" units = "g">
  Used to flag when the mass of a piece or stage has changed.
</tolerance>

<tolerance name="min_size_changed" value = "10.0" units = "mm3">
  Used to flag when the size of volume of a piece or stage has changed.
</tolerance>

 <tolerance name="min_org_changed" value = "1.0" units = "mm">
  This is used to flag when equipment or route components
  have been moved.
</tolerance>

 <tolerance name="min_rot_changed" value = ".01" units = "mm">
  This is used to flag when equipment or route components
  have been rotated.  It's hard to relate the value to something
  physical like degrees or radians.  The routine basically draws unit
  vectors from the origin along the x,y,z directions.  It then compares
  the distance between the end points of these vectors.  
</tolerance>

</tolerances>
